Name: Nguyễn Quốc Trọng Nghĩa

Email: nghia.nguyen170192@gmail.com

Phone: +84908170192

Skype: nghia.nguyen170192

Address: 497/24/19 Phan Văn Trị Street, Ward 5, Go Vap District,

Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

LinkedIn: vn.linkedin.com/in/nghianguyen170192/

Personal Qualities

I am an active IT learner. I always improve my coding skills by implementing new frameworks/libraries or new technologies and customizing them. My expertise is handling backend framework as well as having experience with frontend development, which is involved in building responsive website layout using HTML5/CSS/JavaScript. I am familiar with software development processes such as Scrum and Agile methodology.

I work hard and improve steadily by learning new knowledge in order to have better quality in IT field. I also have good communication with other colleagues and have good attitude toward deadline and other pressures.

Skills

- o **Programming Languages**: HTML5/CSS 3, JavaScript, C#, ASP.NET MVC 5
- o Frontend: Bootstrap, JQuery and responsive web design
- o **Database:** MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server.
- o Editor Tools: Visual Studio, SQL Server Management Tool, Sublime Text
- o Source version control tools: Git, Team Foundation Server (TFS), SVN
- o **Process management tools:** Team Foundation Server (TFS), Trello, Jira
- o Concepts: OOP, Design Patterns, DI, SOLID
- o Software Development Process: Scrum, Agile.
- o **Operating Systems:** Window and MacOs
- Communication tools: Skype/Skype for business, Slack
- o **English:** IELTS 6.5
- o Fluent in English communication via mail, phone and conference call.
- o Teamwork, critical thinking, time management, problems analyzing and solving.

Education

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology University Vietnam

Bachelor of Information Technology: 2011-2014

Work Experience

03/2017 - Now: Software Developer at SAI Digital

Company Homepage: http://www.sai-digital.com

- o Learning and working with Microsoft Dynamics CRM 2011.
- o Programming WebAPI with authentication for each 3rd parties to use(Zalo, Facebook chatbot)
- Developing console applications to run daily and send data to 3rd parties API (Zalo, Facebook chatbot)
- o Monitoring SQL database performance.
- o Planning to implement web portal for user to check all the report using Highchart.js
- o Maintaining current system and fixing known bugs/errors



12/2015 – 02/2017: Software Engineer at Harveynash Viet Nam

Company Homepage: http://www.harveynash.com/vn/

- o Worked with employee management system.
- o Developed functions using Microsoft SQL Server.
- o Designed audit report (show history changes from a table) using triggers
- o Contributed great effort on refactor, maintenance and optimization.
- Worked with SSRS reports(RDLC, RDL)
- o Used SCRUM process.
- Used TFS for source version control and process management.
- Communicated with Project Managers, Product Owners to estimate time for each backlogs via Skype calls, Slack.

11/2014 – 12/2015: Web developer at Amaris

Company Homepage: http://amaris.com/en

- o Worked with several internal ERP apps.
- o Programed apps backend using only ASP.NET MVC 4, 5.
- o Designed database/tables using Microsoft SQL Server.
- o Contributed great effort on refactor, maintenance and optimization.
- o Implement company security package for several apps
- o Designed responsive UI using Bootstrap, HTML5/CSS, JavaScript/Jquery/AJAX.
- o Implemented and customized other external libraries such as XEditable, Select2, Google Place API and International Telephone Input....
- o Generated data reports to Excel/XML format
- o Modified modify internal/external libraries to fit app's requirements.
- o Worked with JSON, XML and XSD format.
- o Used SCRUM process.
- Experienced with using management tool: TFS for both code (branch, merge, checkin and checkout) and process management: manage backlogs and sprints for each app.
- o Communicated with Project Managers, Application Owners to estimate time for each backlogs via Skype calls/conference calls.
- o Helped colleagues when they had problems using frameworks, libraries or improving performance.

06/2014 – 09/2014: Internship as Web Developer at Evil Genius Technologies.

Company Homepage: http://evilgeniustechnologies.com/

- o Worked with several web app projects using ASP.NET
- o Implemented new features for several projects using external framework/libraries such as Amazon Glacier, PayPal, Parse Database, MailChimp.
- o Deployed successfully ASP.NET web apps using AppHarbor hosting server hooked with BitBucket.
- o Experienced with using management tool: Pivotal Tracker, BitBucket.
- o Contributed great effort to refactoring old code and fixing web app errors.
- Designed frontend single page application using Bootstrap, BackboneJS

06/2013 – 12/2013: DND Media Part-time programmer.

Company Homepage: http://dndmedia.vn/

- o Worked with C#, .NET, SQL Server.
- o Built an application generating 10 random characters for lottery and interacts with SQL Database Server for Kinh Do.
- o Built a SMS service for a game show using text message for registration and voting.